Garrett Gutierrez

gagmac@gmail.com (424) 533-0173

https://main--garett-gutierrez-portfolio.netlify.app/ https://github.com/garrettperson https://www.linkedin.com/in/garrett-gutierrez-1b5ab8132/

Web Developer

Summary: Individual with experience building websites, front-end and back-end. Proficient with modern web development technologies. Conceptualizes, designs, and codes responsive websites and pages. Integrates data from various back-end services, databases and APIs. Builds sites to work across browsers and device platforms (desktop, tablet, smartphone). Builds partnerships and works collaboratively with others to meet shared objectives. Excellent attention to detail and quality of work.

Qualifications:

- HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Git, SQL, Sequelize, MongoDB, Mongoose, Express.js, React, Node.js, GraphQL
- Other Technical Skills: Type 55 WPM, Microsoft Office (Word, PowerPoint, Excel), Google Drive, Slack, Adobe Premiere Pro, Adobe Creative Cloud
- Created a variety of user-friendly interactive websites, both front-end and back-end
- Debugged existing code and corrected defects
- Wrote and reviewed documentation on GitHub and other websites
- Provided recommendations for improving documentation and development process standards
- Analyzed user requirements to derive website design
- Assisted in the design, development, implementation, and sustainment of software
- User-focused and product-minded
- Built flexible, cross-browser compatible websites

Education / Training:

UCLA Extension, Los Angeles, CA – Full Stack Web Development Coding Bootcamp University of California, Los Angeles, CA - Bachelor of Arts in Philosophy

Experience:

JagTag Enterprises, Redondo Beach, CA - Training and Development

2011-Present

- Compose, prepare, proofread, and format a variety of written materials using MS Word and PowerPoint including resumes, contracts, request for proposals/proposals, training materials, and presentations.
- Covey complex ideas in a way that people with less technical skills can understand.
- Respond tactfully to all staff, client, and public inquiries over-the-phone, in-person, and by email in a timely
 and efficient manner. Offer encouraging, supportive, and well-informed recommendations and solutions while
 assisting others with dispute and discrepancy resolution, requests for information and services, and the
 completion of required forms. Organize, plan and implement best practices for resume writing.
- Engage in effective customer service techniques with challenging clients from diverse demographics of all ages and socioeconomic backgrounds in a fast-paced high-stress work environment; resolving client concerns by identifying the root cause of client problems and working with others to offer innovative solutions.

Freelance Work, Los Angeles, CA

2015-Present

- Provide Catering Services for Fusion Events for events up to 200 individuals (2023-Present).
- Deliver dozens of meals weekly from a multitude of different restaurants to clients all over the Greater Los Angeles Area through DoorDash (2015-Present).

Ambulnz, Torrance, CA - Emergency Medical Technician - Basic

2020-2021

• Assisted up to 20 patients weekly, completing confidential and detailed patient care reports, submitting reports to quality control. Answered up to 20 calls daily, sorted employee documents and data in Google Drive.

Freelance Work - Film/Event Production, Los Angeles, CA

2014-2020

- Assisted with manpower planning, verifying hours for crews/extras on dozens of production sets, communicating details to production manager and producer in high stakes/fast paced environments.
- Scheduled videos, film shoots, and meetings among crew members.
- Helped organize, coordinate, and execute dozens of film shoots and events including Lifetime Movies and bonus features for "Despicable Me 3" and "Crimson Peak."
- Worked effectively with teams of two to 60 individuals, including high-profile individuals, to ensure productions remained confidential, streamlined, and as engaging as possible.
- Read materials and watched videos to build video editing and videography knowledge, editing dozens of videos
 using Adobe Premiere and Final Cut Pro. Managed time and projects while working independently for multiple
 clients. Created captions for a documentary film and assisted with editing process.